Gene Basset Papers
Gene Basset Papers
1962-1969
Basset, Gene, 1927-
13.6 linear ft.
Original artwork for over 1,300 syndicated editorial cartoons and proofs.
149716
Biographical History
Gene Basset (1927- ) is an American cartoonist primarily known for his editorial cartoons.
Born in Brooklyn, New York on July 24, 1927, Gene Basset served with the United States Coast Guard from 1944 to 1946. He then attended the University of Missouri from 1946 to 1947 and also studied at Cooper Union from 1947 to 1950. Basset also studied at Brooklyn College, the Art Students League and the Pratt Institute. He received degrees in both art and psychology.
During his career, Basset worked in several artistic capacities. From 1951 to 1953, Basset was a sketch artist at the Indianapolis Times. He then drew sports and theatrical cartoons for the Brooklyn Eagle before working as a sports cartoonist at the Boston Post. In 1962, after a brief stint as the Honolulu Star Bulletin's first editorial cartoonist, Basset became the chief editorial cartoonist with Scripps Howard newspapers. Beginning in 1972, his work was also syndicated by the United Feature Syndicate. In 1982, Basset joined the staff of the Atlanta Journal Constitution.
Basset was a member of the National Cartoonists Society and the American Association of Editorial Cartoonists of which he was president in 1973. Basset also taught art at the Famous Artists School in Westport, Connecticut from 1957 to 1962. The Population Institute named one of his cartoons the Best Editorial Cartoon in 1974 and his cartoons were reprinted in magazines such as Time and Newsweek. His work has been exhibited at the Pratt Institute and in 2005 drawings done by Basset during a trip to Vietnam were exhibited at Gustavus Adolphus College.
Basset retired from the Atlanta Journal Constitution at the end of 1992. Gene Basset's son, Brian Basset worked as an editorial cartoonist for the Seattle Times during the 1980s and 1990s and is now a comic strip artist working on Adam at Home and Red and Rover.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Gene Basset Papers consist primarily of original artwork for editorial cartoons as well as proofs.
Cartoons (1962-1969) contains over 1,300 original cartoons. Most of these cartoons are dated. They were drawn by Basset while he was with Scripps Howard.
Basset's cartoons depict national and international events during this time period. Receiving frequent treatment were the political pursuits of Barry Goldwater and changes within the Republican Party, as well as the escalation and increasing cost of the Vietnam War.
Worth noting are Basset's cartoons about inflation, Congressional pay raises and the regulation of smoking and tobacco advertising. Also, following the 1968 presidential election there are several cartoons about the electoral system and electoral college. Also of interest are cartoons depicting Senator Ted Kennedy and the Chappaquiddick scandal and President Richard Nixon's attempt to appoint Clement Haynsworth to the Supreme Court.
Basset worked with pen and ink and also crayon on illustration board and paper. Traces of pencil are visible and some contain zipatone dot screening. Captions appear in ink. Original art varies in size, however most cartoons are 11 1/2" x 14".
Proofs includes six undated black and white proofs of cartoons otherwise not appearing in the collection.
Arrangement of the Collection
Cartoons are arranged primarily in chronological order. Two boxes of undated cartoons are arranged alphabetically by caption.
Related Material
has collections of over one hundred cartoonists. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Cartoonists; Scripps-Howard.; United Feature Syndicate.; Basset, Gene, 1927-; Gaulle, Charles de, 1890-1970 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Goldwater, Barry M. (Barry Morris), 1909-1998 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Ho Chi Minh, 1890-1969 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Humphrey, Hubert H. (Hubert Horatio), 1911-1978 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Wallace, George C. (George Corley), 1919-1998 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Khrushchev, Nikita Sergeevich, 1894-1971 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Mao, Zedong, 1893-1976 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Kennedy, Robert F., 1925-1968 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; McNamara, Robert S., 1916-2009 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Kennedy, Edward M. (Edward Moore), 1932-2009 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-1994 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- ) -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Democratic Party (U.S.) -- Caricatures and cartoons.; United States. Congress -- Caricatures and cartoons.; American wit and humor, Pictorial.; Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.; Cartoonists -- United States.; Civil rights movements -- United States -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Cigarette industry -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Cold War -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Demonstrations -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Editorial cartoons -- United States.; Elections -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; World politics -- 1945-1989 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; United States -- Politics and government -- 1963-1969 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Cartoons (humorous images); Proofs (printed matter); Editorial cartoons.; Cartoonists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Gene Basset, 1965, 1968-1969, 1972 and Thom Rooke, 2016
Inventory
- Cartoons, 1,319 items
  - Cartoons, 1962, Jan (Oversize 1)
    Jan 13: That's one thing we've plenty of, Raul: Fidel Castro, Raul Castro, Latin America
  - Cartoons, 1962, Oct (Oversize 1)
    Oct 13: We're neutral all right, we just happen to lean to the left: Algeria, Indonesia, Ghana, India
  - Cartoons, 1962, Nov (Oversize 1)
    Nov 3: One casualty - we lost Krishna Menon: Mao Zedong
  - Cartoons, 1962, Dec (Oversize 1)
    Dec 15: No thanks, I swore off: Jawaharlal Nehru. Ghana, Indonesia, Burma, United Arab Republic
  - Cartoons, 1963, Jan (Oversize 1)
    Jan 4: In the name of peace, law and order - surrender!: United Nations
    Jan 7: Don't they know there's no God in Russia!: Nikita Khrushchev, religion
    Jan 22: Mine to have and mine to hold!: Charles De Gaulle, nuclear weapons
    Jan 31: A tree grows in Cuba: Fidel Castro, Cuba
  - Cartoons, 1963, Feb (Oversize 1)
    Feb 6: Anyway you look at it it's going up: Robert McNamara, Kenneth Keating, Cuba
    Feb 21: DeGaulle Supreme: Charles De Gaulle
    Feb 27: Squeeze play: Fidel Castro, Raul Castro
  - Cartoons, 1963, Mar (Oversize 1)
    Mar 9: Old Faithful: Sukarno
    Mar 11: It's that western art and jazz that gives me headaches: communism, Nikita Khrushchev
    Mar 13: The sword of Nasser: Gamal Abdel Nasser, Jordan, Saudi Arabia, Israel
    Head hunting: Robert McNamara, John McClellan
    Mar 27: And now my latest Spring creation: Berlin, Nikita Khrushchev
    Mar 29: Out of the trenches by 1967...or thereabouts: South Korea
  - Cartoons, 1963, Apr (Oversize 1)
    Apr 1: Gee, I hope our kids get to see this: nature
    Apr 3: Isn't it marvelous the progress we've made with Comrade Khrushchev: Nikita Khrushchev
    Apr 6: Vot means this code word macaroni?: Nikita Khrushchev
    Apr 10: Launched: Lester Bowles Pearson, John Diefenbaker
    Apr 13: No high hard ones...got it?: John F. Kennedy, steel industry
    Apr 14: You know, this stuff is actually digestable: new expense account rules
    Apr 15: One drop does not a thaw make: Dean Rusk, Charles De Gaulle
    Apr 17: Don't run off now: Sukarno, foreign aid
    Apr 23: Going...going...: Laos, communism
    Apr 30: Backlash: Dominican Republic, François Duvalier
  - Cartoons, 1963, May (Oversize 1)
    May 7: There, more comfortable: deficit, C. Douglas Dillon
    May 9: Bookworms...Eggheads...Traitors!: George Wallace, students
    May 14: We ain't givin'up our culture without a fight: civil rights
    May 18: Eat it with vigah: Orville Freeman, farming
    May 20: Hear anything?: railroad industry, unions
    May 21: The leaning tower of Washington: national debt
    May 22: Breakthrough: civil rights, demonstrations, Supreme Court
    May 23: General Freeman reporting, Sir!: Orville Freeman, John F. Kennedy
    May 29: You forgot this: integration, Supreme Court
  - Cartoons, 1963, Jun (Oversize 1)
    Jun 1: Just dead wood, fellers: U.S. Constitution, Congress, Supreme Court
    Jun 10: Double, double toil and trouble: Harold Macmillan
    Jun 14: As the polls go: Nelson Rockefeller, Barry Goldwater
    Jun 18: Children, we will now start class by reading a text book: Supreme Court, school prayer
    Jun 19: What else is new, Mr. Prime Minister?: Harold Macmillan
    Jun 20: Offense and Defense: civil rights bill
    Jun 22: Pack up your troubles in your old kit bag and smile, smile, smile: civil rights, taxes, Medicare, John F. Kennedy, Pierre Salinger, unemployment
    Jun 24: European street scene: John F. Kennedy, Charles De Gaulle
    Jun 25: Meeting of the minds: Nikita Khrushchev, Mao Zedong
    Jun 26: Hold it...In my kitchen I do the cooking: Congress, civil rights bill
    Jun 28: Watering time: Congress, civil rights bill
  - Cartoons, 1963, Jul (Oversize 1)
    Jul 1: Strange music: Karl Marx, Mao Zedong, Nikita Khrushchev
    Jul 2: Rumanian Rhapsody: Romania, Nikita Khrushchev
    Jul 5: Another twin launching: nuclear weapons, John F. Kennedy, Nikita Khrushchev
    Jul 6: The passing scene: Barry Goldwater, Nelson Rockefeller
    Jul 8: Eyeball to eyeball: Nikita Khrushchev, Mao Zedong
    Jul 9: Perils of Pauline Public: railroad industry, unions
    Jul 11: Fear not....We've saved you for 19 more days: railroad industry, unions, strikes
    Jul 12: Hi Ave ...It's the new me: peace, Nikita Khrushchev, Averell Harriman
    Jul 13: Boys, it stands to reason...the Commies planted the Negro in our country: communism, civil rights
    Jul 13: Vigah on the rocks: John F. Kennedy, weapons
    Jul 15: Shhh, there it is....again: nuclear weapons, Nikita Khrushchev, John F. Kennedy
    Jul 18: We're not selfish or prejudiced or hateful...just superior: George Wallace, Ross Barnett
    Jul 19: What you need is a little reshaping: stock market, Securities Exchange Commission
    Jul 20: Fore!: taxes, securities
    Jul 22: Remember class...there are two kinds of Communists... the good and the rotten, imperialistic, warmongering, lunatics: communism
    Jul 23: Razzle-Dazzle: Congress, railroad industry, John F. Kennedy
    Jul 24: Man, smell that fresh air: nuclear weapons, John F. Kennedy, Nikita Khrushchev, Harold Macmillan
    Jul 25: Ike was here: John F. Kennedy, Dwight Eisenhower
    Jul 25: On site inspection: nuclear weapons
    Jul 25: Let's keep it that way!: nature
    Jul 30: The kibitzer: nuclear weapons, Charles De Gaulle, John F. Kennedy, Nikita Khrushchev, Harold Macmillan
    Jul 31: Back at the old stand: North Korea, Mao Zedong
  - Cartoons, 1963, Aug (Oversize 1)
    Aug 2: Sit-in: railroad industry, John F. Kennedy
    Aug 3: Lowering the standard: civil rights
    Aug 7: No future: school dropouts
    Aug 10: A tree wilts in Washington: nature
    Aug 12: It's what's inside that counts: nuclear weapons
    Aug 13: Sorry, you're holding us back: taxes, John F. Kennedy
    Aug 15: Time for a switch: Congress, railroad industry strike
    Aug 16: Remember Junior, no cookies until you clean up: Congress, deficit"
    Aug 19: No dog days here: Congress, civil rights, nuclear weapons, education, taxes
  - Cartoons, 1963, Oct (Oversize 1)
    Oct 3: [Editors note: No caption with this cartoon.]: civil rights
    Oct 28: Grounded: space exploration, Soviet Union
    Oct 29: We're off on the road to Morocco: Algeria, Ben Bella, Gamal Abdel Nasser
    Oct 31: Well, here goes: Bobby Baker
  - Cartoons, 1963, Nov (Oversize 2)
    Nov 1: Damn the deficit...full pay raise ahead!: Congress, economy
    Nov 2: When you catch up I'll debate you: Barry Goldwater, Nelson Rockefeller, John F. Kennedy
    Nov 2: Toppled: South Vietnam coup
    Nov 4: Congratulations: South Vietnam coup, Dominican Republic coup, John F. Kennedy
    Nov 6: Inspection: Berlin
    Nov 7: There must be a trend here somewhere: elections, Republican Party, Democratic Party
    Nov 8: I see Rocky's switched to the regulation outfit: Nelson Rockefeller, Barry Goldwater
    Nov 9: Shaping up: foreign aid, Congress
    Nov 11: Evolution?: Barry Goldwater
    Nov 12: Great, Miss Trask...You're our twist instructor: Congress
    Nov 13: How d'you like the new model?: Jimmy Hoffa, Teamsters
    Nov 14: I'll show those no-good Republicans: civil rights, Charles Halleck, Richard Russell
    Nov 15: A toast to the 'Spirit of Moscow,' Mr. President.: John F. Kennedy, Nikita Khrushchev
    Nov 19: Still breathing, Doc?: Medicare, Congress
    Nov 20: You boys know the rules...murder each other.: Nelson Rockefeller, Barry Goldwater, Richard Nixon
    Nov 22: Tis the season to be jolly...: Christmas, AT&T
    Nov 27: No time for politics: Republican Party, Democratic Party
    Nov 29: [Editor's note: No Caption with Cartoon]: John F. Kennedy, Lyndon B. Johnson
  - Cartoons, 1963, Dec (Oversize 2)
    Dec 5: What's there to blockade? Just me and my shadow: Fidel Castro, Venezuela
    Dec 6: Drip, drip, drip...: Barry Goldwater
    Dec 7: Security: railroad industry, unions
    Dec 10: Dr. Johnson...wanted in surgery: budget
    Dec 11: Yes Virgin Ya, there is a Santa Claus.: consumerism, Christmas
    Dec 12: Darn those late mailers: Christmas
    Dec 13: Sure I said chop away but not in my backyard: Robert McNamara, Congress
    Dec 16: Native bearer: cotton industry, taxes
    Dec 17: Nice of that ship to toss us life preservers: Honduras, Dominican Republic
    Dec 18: You're allowed visitors, not visiting: Berlin Wall
    Dec 20: Silent Night: traffic fatalities
    Dec 21: On your mark…: Lyndon B. Johnson
    Dec 23: We're dreaming of a White Christmas: Vietnam War
    Dec 27: Stop the stampede!: Barry Goldwater, Lyndon B. Johnson, Congress
    Dec 30: [Editors, note...no caption with cartoon]: farming, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Dec 31: ...And everywhere the Senate went the lamb was sure to go: Bobby Baker
  - Cartoons, 1964, Jan (Oversize 2)
    Jan 3: The Great Ice Age: Nikita Khrushchev, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Jan 4: [Editors, note...no caption with cartoon.]: Barry Goldwater
    Jan 6: Now then, where were we?: Middle East, Pope Paul VI
    Jan 7: All fagged out: smoking
    Jan 8: One at a time, comrades, one at a time: Cuba, Fidel Castro, Spain, Britain
    Jan 9: It's me all right, but I can't believe it: Lyndon B. Johnson, budget
    Jan 10: New roundup: poverty
    Jan 13: Moment of truth: smoking
    Jan 15: Working both sides of the field: tobacco industry, smoking
    Jan 17: Handicap: taxes, education
    Jan 18: Can I trade this in for a Senator's helmet?: John Glenn
    Jan 21: Infection: Africa, Zanzibar
    Jan 23: Look what I got: Bobby Baker, Democratic Party, Republican Party
    Jan 24: The natives are restless: Africa, Mao Zedong, Fidel Castro, Nikita Khrushchev
    Jan 25: Vitamin B-aker: Bobby Baker
    Jan 30: Well, I'll be a: space exploration, Soviet Union
    Jan 31: Glug, glug, glug……: Dean Rusk, Vietnam War, Lyndon B. Johnson
  - Cartoons, 1964, Feb (Oversize 2)
    Feb 1: Follow me, men!: Charles De Gaulle, neutrality
    Feb 3: Probably one of those woman drivers: space exploration
    Feb 3: What conflict of interest?: Congress, armed forces
    Feb 4: Patience.... we're still debating what sort of life you'll lead.: civil rights
    Feb 8: The paper curtain: Cuba, Britain, France
    Feb 8: [Editors: no caption needed]: Civil War, civil rights, Abraham Lincoln, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Feb 12: African coloring book: communism, Ghana, Kwame Nkrumah, Africa
    Feb 13: Shish-kebab: Cyprus, Makarios III
    Feb 15: Double dynamite: Panama, nationalism, communism
    Feb 15: A well fed Communist is less dangerous: Fidel Castro, Britain, Lord Home, trade
    Feb 18: Sapped?: elections, Nelson Rockefeller, Barry Goldwater, Henry Cabot Lodge Jr., Richard Nixon, Margaret Chase Smith
    Feb 19: Reapportionment: Supreme Court, Congress
    Feb 20: Folks, in this simple setting Bobby Baker got his humble start: Bobby Baker
    Feb 21: Is that me?: racism (in the northern U.S.)
    Feb 24: Exposed rear: Vietnam War
    Feb 25: Look Mr. President...you run your country and I'll run mine: longshoreman's union, trade, Soviet Union
    Feb 26: Experimental medicine: taxes, economy
    Feb 27: Containment: Vietnam War
    Feb 29: The Greeks have words for it: Russia, Cyprus, Nikita Khrushchev, Makarios III
  - Cartoons, 1964, Mar (Oversize 2)
    Mar 4: You're lucky we warned in time about smoking: smoking, tobacco industry
    Mar 6: Very well, put it out if you insist: Cyprus, Makarios III, United Nations
    Mar 7: [Editors, note: no caption needed]: Congress
    Mar 9: There's your plot...a typical day in Dallas: movies
    Mar 11: A tree grows in New Hampshire: Henry Cabot Lodge, Jr.
    Mar 14: Yankee come home!: Nelson Rockefeller, Barry Goldwater, Henry Cabot Lodge, Vietnam War
    Mar 17: Human renewal program: Lyndon B. Johnson, War on Poverty
    Mar 18: We're not very far apart: Panama, Lyndon B. Johnson, Roberto Francisco Chiari Remón
    Mar 19: What's DeGaulle up to by not undermining our Latin American Policy?: Charles De Gaulle, Latin America, Lyndon B. Johnson, Dean Rusk
    Mar 20: Courage, son, courage: Congress, foreign aid, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Mar 21: I call the pitches...got it!: Robert F. Kennedy, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Mar 23: [Editors, note - no caption]: daily agenda at the White House
    Mar 24: And that takes care of that account: United Nations, Nikita Khrushchev
    Mar 25: Wild pitch: civil riots, riots
    Mar 26: The brakes, fellers, the brakes: United Auto Workers, auto industry, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Mar 27: Game called on account of darkness: Bobby Baker
    Mar 28: Patience and fortitude: Vietnam War
    Mar 30: When a feller needs a friend: Alaska, natural disasters
  - Cartoons, 1964, Apr (Oversize 3)
    Apr 2: Excuse me, Mr. President....Where's the fire?: Lyndon B. Johnson
    Apr 3: Freshly backed: Brazil, João Goulart
    Apr 4: Now there's a salesman!: Richard Nixon, business
    Apr 7: Foreigner!: Henry Cabot Lodge, Jr., Barry Goldwater, elections
    Apr 9: Brewed in Wisconsin: George Wallace, elections
    Apr 11: Pauline's pal: railroad industry, strikes, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Apr 11: The prospector: George Wallace, elections
    Apr 11: His Chinese tailor: Mao Zedong, Nikita Khrushchev
    Apr 13: Emergence: civil rights
    Apr 14: Hey man, we're using this kind of torch: civil rights, extremism
    Apr 15: I haven't got the heart to tell Comrade Mao that Khrushchev isn't dead: Mao Zedong, Nikita Khrushchev
    Apr 16: Choice of weapons: Robert McNamara, Curtis Lemay
    Apr 18: Look what I created: civil rights, extremism
    Apr 18: ...While back at Utopia: Nikita Khrushchev, Mao Zedong
    Apr 20: :!!!?*!*!#....?!: Vietnam War, Laos, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Apr 20: Squeeze play: school prayer
    Apr 21: Not exactly an ax: Barry Goldwater
    Apr 22: Banzai!: Henry Cabot Lodge, Jr., Richard Nixon, Barry Goldwater, Vietnam War
    Apr 23: I guess the idea just ran out of gas: civil rights, World's Fair, demonstrations
    Apr 23: My hero: Lyndon B. Johnson, railroad industry
    Apr 24: Don't just stand there...go settle a strike!: Barry Goldwater, Republican Party, Richard Nixon, Nelson Rockefeller
    Apr 29: Jab, jab, jab,....night and day: Lyndon B. Johnson, Republican Party
  - Cartoons, 1964, May (Oversize 3)
    May 1: Next: George Wallace, elections
    May 4: Windstorm: civil rights legislation
    May 5: Stick to your guns, Mak: Nikita Khrushchev, Makarios III
    May 6: Civil rights demonstration: Africa, Nikita Khrushchev, Mao Zedong
    May 7: It was a great fight Mom....and I won: George Wallace, elections
    May 8: I repeat...to Hell with American aid!: Sukarno
    May 9: Remember me, your conscience?: economy, Congress
    May 11: American-made tombstones: Vietnam War
    May 12: I've come to save you from the infidels: Gamal Abdel Nasser, Nikita Khrushchev
    May 13: To begin with, Mr. President...Vietnam is a Hell of a place to fight a war: Vietnam War, Robert McNamara, Lyndon B. Johnson
    May 14: Hitchhiker: Barry Goldwater, Richard Nixon
    May 15: Lady Bird, oh Lady Bird...I know you're there, Lady Bird: poverty, Republican Party
    May 18: [Editors: no caption with cartoon]: Barry Goldwater, Nelson Rockefeller
    May 19: Teamwork: China, Vietnam War, Laos, communism, nationalism
    May 20: Giddyap: Nelson Rockefeller, Henry Cabot Lodge, Jr., Barry Goldwater
    May 21: Clear the beach....tidal wave!: Strom Thurmond, civil rights, George Wallace
    May 23: Holding Action: Lyndon B. Johnson, Asia
    May 25: Barbeque, anyone?: trade, Lyndon B. Johnson, Soviet Union
    May 26: Cinderella?: Barry Goldwater, Milton Eisenhower
    May 27: This will be a long, hard war." Sec. McNamara: Vietnam War
    May 28: ...and now Senator Goldwater will say a few words to balance his previous remarks: Barry Goldwater
    May 29: ...an' the sun comes up like thunder outer China 'crost the bay!...Kipling: China, Asia
    May 30: One of our Pillars is missing!: presidency, vice presidency
  - Cartoons, 1964, Jun (Oversize 3)
    Jun 1: Harbinger: Vietnam War
    Jun 2: Tiger in the streets: racial violence
    Jun 4: California or bust - GOP nomination or bust: Barry Goldwater, elections
    Jun 6: Come home...all is forgiven: Barry Goldwater, Republican Party
    Jun 6: Pop!: Barry Goldwater
    Jun 8: D Day at Goldwater Beach: Dwight Eisenhower, William Scranton
    Jun 9: Plain of Jars: Laos, Vietnam, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Jun 11: Cut: civil rights
    Jun 12: Noting our giant upward strides...all in favor of a pay hike raise your hand: Congress
    Jun 13: I'm late, I'm late...for a very important date: William Scranton, Barry Goldwater, elections
    Jun 15: Chip, chip, chip...: William Scranton, elections
  - Cartoons, 1964, Jul (Oversize 3)
    Jul 7: What's in a name?: Milton Eisenhower, William Scranton
    Jul 8: Moment of decision: Republican Party, John Birch Society
    Jul 9: Tell me Doc...how do I learn to live with Goldwater?: Republican Party, Barry Goldwater
    Jul 10: Jack in the box: funeral expenses
    Jul 20: Un-Civil-Ized Rites: civil rights, extremism, Ku Klux Klan
    Jul 21: Bobb, we need you where you are: Robert F. Kennedy, Lyndon B. Johnson, elections
    Jul 21: The Plank: Barry Goldwater, Republican Party
    Jul 23: Here's your dough for the day, Fidel: Fidel Castro, Organization of American States
    Jul 24: Neutrals of Southeast Asia, arise!: Charles De Gaulle, Mao Zedong
    Jul 25: No drought: Lyndon B. Johnson, elections
    Jul 28: Still at the wheel: Jimmy Hoffa, Robert F. Kennedy
    Jul 29: I have nothing to hide and besides, I'm not showing it: Congress
  - Cartoons, 1964, Aug (Oversize 3)
    Aug 1: Take it from me...this boy you can trust: Fidel Castro, Nikita Khrushchev
    Aug 1: Bullseye: space exploration, Nikita Khrushchev
    Aug 3: Cool it, man, cool it: civil rights, demonstrations
    Aug 6: Paper Tigers!: Vietnam War
    Aug 7: A tree grows in Mississippi: Mississippi, civil rights lynchings
    Aug 10: Whatever brand of firewater they're drinking, I'm gonna bottle it: NATO, Cyprus, Mao Zedong, Nikita Khrushchev